<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Eklavya's Blog - About Me</title><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/feed/about-me.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2017-12-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>How I began Juggling</title><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/how-i-began-juggling.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-12-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Eklavya Sharma</name></author><id>tag:sharmaeklavya2.github.io,2017-12-02:/blog/how-i-began-juggling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since childhood, juggling had captivated me and I always wanted to learn how to juggle.
However, all my initial attempts to learn it failed. It was so difficult.
I couldn't make any progress even when I tried for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one day (in 2011, when I was around 16 years …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since childhood, juggling had captivated me and I always wanted to learn how to juggle.
However, all my initial attempts to learn it failed. It was so difficult.
I couldn't make any progress even when I tried for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one day (in 2011, when I was around 16 years old),
I saw a documentary-ish thing on TV about juggling.
According to it, there are multiple ways of juggling. Those ways are called 'patterns'.
The pattern below is called the 'shower' pattern:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Shower pattern" src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/51.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out that the shower is a difficult juggling pattern.
There's a juggling pattern easier than the shower, called 'cascade':&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cascade pattern" src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/3.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All my life, I had been trying to learn the shower
because that was the only juggling pattern I could imagine.
But as soon as I realized that cascade was easier, I tried learning that instead.
And this time I made some progress.
After around a week of practice, I could juggle for up to 10 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't remember why, but I didn't pursue juggling any further then.
I resumed it 3 years later.
I got better at cascade and then started learning other juggling patterns (including the shower).
Near the end of my first year at BITS (2014),
I bought juggling &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juggling_club"&gt;clubs&lt;/a&gt;.
By October 2017, I knew around 25 patterns with 3 balls, 8 patterns with 4 balls, the 5-ball cascade
and 7 patterns with 3 clubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't make much progress in 2016 and 2017.
I have been busy with studies and haven't been able to juggle regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find videos documenting my juggling skills on youtube:
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xYrnQMHfDNE&amp;amp;list=PLACN_dyOcd_WSIzGV-4hVCQyQFmzKH1kb"&gt;Juggling by me (October 2015)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Juggling"></category><category term="About Me"></category></entry></feed>