<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Eklavya's Blog - Dream</title><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/feed/dream.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2023-12-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Forest Nightmare</title><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/dream3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-12-21T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-12-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Eklavya Sharma</name></author><id>tag:sharmaeklavya2.github.io,2023-12-21:/blog/dream3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a nightmare today which I think can be made into a good horror movie.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a nightmare today. Although I never like nightmares, I was amused by this dream's concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="scene-1"&gt;Scene 1&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#scene-1" title="Permanent link"&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was camping with friends, in a forest full of tall coniferous trees.
Despite a sunny day, the forest was unusually dark and the weather was cool,
with a hint of fog in the distance.
The ponds, waterfalls, and the rocky terrain were a delightful change from
the plains of Urbana-Champaign and the polluted building-laden landscape of Delhi-Gurugram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a fireside chat at night, we got into our tents and went to sleep.
In the middle of the night, we were awakened by footsteps in the distance, made obvious
by the rustling of leaves fallen on the ground.
We took out our flashlights and walked out of our tents.
We searched a few feet away from our tents to see if a person or an animal was nearby.
We didn't find anyone or anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we got back into our tents. Where's Peter?!
How did it take us a few &lt;em&gt;minutes&lt;/em&gt; to realize that he was missing?!
He must have walked a little too far from the tent while searching for the footsteps.
We went out looking for him, this time holding hands to prevent others from getting lost.
Finally, we saw a person lying on the ground. Was this Peter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked closer and saw Peter lying supine on the ground, blood pooled around his torso.
He was stabbed in the chest and his throat was slit.
His face was pale white and a little disfigured, and tears of blood had flowed through his shut eyes.
We heard footsteps again, behind us.
When we turned our flashlight, we saw a glimpse of a tall person
who quickly hid behind a tree.
It was wearing a black robe with a hood covering its face,
and held a dagger that was covered in blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do we do now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="scene-2"&gt;Scene 2&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#scene-2" title="Permanent link"&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a remote town in the Himalayas, lies a thick forest full of coniferous trees.
This forest is apparently haunted and people have been known to go missing.
Locals claimed that they have seen a ghost while collecting firewood.
They identified her as the only daughter of Sir Eddington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They described her as a tall bald lady, dressed in a black gown, with a hood covering her head.
Her face was gray and flaky, as if burned.
Usually, she didn't have eyes, only empty sockets for where her eyes should have been.
One witness claimed to have seen her with large round yellow eyes and no eyelids.
She held a dagger in her hand, made of sharpened bone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sir Eddington was a ruthless British official, posted to this town when India was a British colony.
His harsh policies made life very difficult for the people living here,
trapping many in predatory work contracts and collecting painfully large taxes.
Her daughter, on the other hand, wanted to stay away from the region's politics.
His wife had died when his daughter was a little child,
and he never prioritized spending time with his daughter,
instead focusing on amassing power and wealth.
Consequently, her daughter found solace in her interests, literature and photography.
She often hung out in the forests, enjoying its beauty and tranquility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exasperated by Sir Eddington's rule, the locals decided to fight back.
At dawn, they attacked his mansion, which was situated at the edge of the forest.
Although Sir Eddington had a small army, it was no match for the locals who had been training
for this day and were experts at navigating the mountainous terrain and hiding in the forest.
They eventually broke into his mansion and captured him.
They beheaded him in front of his mansion, declaring their freedom and the beginning of
a new era free of tyranny. They set fire to his mansion, killing the remaining soldiers,
and his daughter who had been hiding inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They raided his house the next day, foraging for valuables untainted by fire,
and found his daughter, lying on the ground. Her feet and face were covered
with shards of glass, presumably from the mansion's fallen chandeliers.
Tears of blood had flown from her eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="scene-3"&gt;Scene 3&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#scene-3" title="Permanent link"&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lay on the cold marble floor, with a searing pain in my eyes.
My head was heavy and my thoughts garbled. What just happened?
I could smell smoke and hear flames, but I couldn't see anything.
I tried to get up but my body didn't comply. I wanted to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I woke up, I was lying in the forest. The fallen leaves were soft yet crisp.
I got up, but I couldn't see anything. Why can't I open my eyes?
My thoughts were clouded like the forest's fog.
I was lost. I waited for someone to come by but no one came.
So I started wandering the forest. I came across streams, boulders,
and heard birds chirping merrily.
Oh, what a delightful sight it would have been, if only I could see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was alone for what seemed like an eternity.
Finally, I heard footsteps. I approached the person, and shouted for help, but heard no response.
As I crept up behind him, I snapped into a trance. I wanted his eyes.
I grabbed his neck, plucked out his eyes with my sharp nails,
and put them in my face. I could see again!
I don't know why I did this, or why I expected this to work, but it did.
What a delight it was to be able to see once again! The forest was as beautiful as I remembered it.
The next day, however, my elation gradually faded away, just like my sight.
I guess this only works for a short time.
I'll just have to wait for more people to come to the forest.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"></category><category term="Dream"></category></entry><entry><title>Weird dream 2</title><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/dream2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-08-06T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-08-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Eklavya Sharma</name></author><id>tag:sharmaeklavya2.github.io,2022-08-06:/blog/dream2.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a weird 2-part dream today.
The two parts were happening kind-of parallely,
but I'll narrate them sequentially for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-1"&gt;Part 1&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#part-1" title="Permanent link"&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my friends' place expanded from a 2-bedroom apartment to a large mansion/dorm.
Many people were living in it: I, some of my friends, and a few strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a large almost-empty room somewhere in his mansion.
The only furniture in that room was two maroon 3-seater sofas on opposite ends of the room.
I played indoor soccer in that room against a woman, treating the sofas as goals.
That woman is a senior professor at a large US university
(I know who she is but I've never talked to her and I won't name her here).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the game ended, I got hungry and went to the kitchen to have breakfast.
The kitchen was very dirty.
I don't know why, but I had a sudden urge to clean the place before having breakfast.
I washed dishes, cleaned the stove, took out the trash,
threw expired stuff from the fridge, etc.
But even after spending what felt like an eternity, there was still a lot more to be done!
It was as if the kitchen was magically dirtying itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-2"&gt;Part 2&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#part-2" title="Permanent link"&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in high school (in Delhi). It was winter and I was feeling cold.
A mysterious person offered me a black hoodie.
I took it and put it on without asking any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to the sports ground and students saw that large
ice &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stalagmite"&gt;Stalagmites&lt;/a&gt; had formed on the floor.
Students started hurling them in the air like Javelins in random directions.
It was like the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FgJIa3-bv74&amp;amp;t=644s"&gt;unofficial IISc Holi celebration&lt;/a&gt;,
but with a lot less people and ice javelins instead of clothes.
I had to keep dodging them to prevent getting impaled.
I kept telling them this is a bad idea but they all ignored me.
I ran to an edge of the field to reduce the variance in directions of javelins approaching me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then an alien spaceship arrived (stereotypically circular in shape).
It started shooting bombs and lasers at us.
I realized that people wearing black hoodies were unaffected by its lasers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"></category><category term="Dream"></category></entry><entry><title>Weird dream</title><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/dream1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-11-10T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-11-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Eklavya Sharma</name></author><id>tag:sharmaeklavya2.github.io,2020-11-10:/blog/dream1.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a weird 2-part dream today. Here's what happened in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-1"&gt;Part 1&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#part-1" title="Permanent link"&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to get
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vladimir_Putin"&gt;Vladimir Putin&lt;/a&gt;'s signature
on a document (I don't remember why). So he visited my house.
I went to my room to get the form, but I couldn't find it,
even after looking everywhere in my room.
I told him that I couldn't find the form, so I would print another one.
But my printer refused to print because it was low on cyan,
even though the form was completely black-and-white.
I troubleshooted the printer while Putin patiently waited behind me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I'm not a Putin fan. I'm not interested in or aware of Russian politics.
Then why was Putin in my dreams? I have no idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-2"&gt;Part 2&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#part-2" title="Permanent link"&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was attending a lecture at a university.
There was a loud noise outside, so all the students rushed out to see what's going on.
It turns out that &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saraswati"&gt;Saraswati Devi&lt;/a&gt; had
come flying on a huge swan and landed near our lecture building.
Then &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frozen_(2013_film)"&gt;Elsa and Anna&lt;/a&gt;
come out of their labs, hop on the huge swan, and leave with Saraswati.
We get to know that Elsa and Anna are actually PhD students in our university's
biology department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An animal (either an owl or a deer or a human; I forgot which exactly)
walks up to us, claiming to be an agent of Saraswati.
He claims that Elsa and Anna have been chosen by God to complete holy quests.
He offers monetary remuneration to Elsa and Anna's advisor.
The advisor cries, "What will I do with money? You took away my best PhD students.
I may have to restart my experiments from scratch. How will I get
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Academic_tenure"&gt;tenure&lt;/a&gt; now?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I'm not a religious person or a Frozen fan.
Then why were Saraswati and Elsa in my dreams? I have no idea.
Also, I don't think tenure works like that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"></category><category term="Dream"></category></entry></feed>