<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Eklavya's Blog - Juggling</title><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/feed/juggling.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2017-12-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Juggling 101</title><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/juggling-101.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-03T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-12-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Eklavya Sharma</name></author><id>tag:sharmaeklavya2.github.io,2017-12-03:/blog/juggling-101.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a tutorial for those who wish to learn juggling and have absolutely no prior experience. Here you will find links to resources that will help you learn your first juggling pattern and suggestions about what kind of balls to use, what posture you should have, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a tutorial for those who wish to learn juggling and have absolutely no prior experience.
Here you will find links to resources that will help you learn your first juggling pattern
and suggestions about what kind of balls to use, what posture you should have, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting informed and motivated&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn juggling, you should first know what juggling looks like.
Watch these awesome videos, which portray many common styles of juggling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wP8tbLBls_M"&gt;Anthony Gatto's performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cvME9BLYgsw"&gt;World Juggling day Japan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Your first pattern&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first juggling pattern you should learn is the 3-ball cascade.
This is what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/3.gif" title="3-cascade" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people try to begin with the 3-ball shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/51.gif" title="3-shower" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not recommended. The shower is more difficult than the cascade.
Don't even try to learn the shower before the cascade; it will make it more difficult to learn the cascade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out how to learn the cascade by watching instructional videos.
You can find many such videos on YouTube if you search 'cascade juggling tutorial'
(for example, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x2_j6kMg1co"&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Niels Duinker).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you practice the cascade for around 15 minutes a day, you'll be able to learn it in around a week.
Consistency is very important in juggling (for any pattern, not just cascade).
If you don't practice for a few days, you will most likely forget the patterns you haven't mastered.
Practice every day for best results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Get balls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost any not-easily-breakable spherical object of an appropriate size and weight is good enough to juggle,
but we'll discuss the options commonly available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tennis or Cricket balls (not the leather ones): These are what I currently use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sponge balls: These are great if you're juggling in an environment with a lot of breakables.
  But they bounce off from hands and they lack weight.
  I learned juggling with them, but I recommend not starting with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beanbags: They're small bags filled tight with small beans or beads so that they are almost spherical.
  They don't bounce and roll off, which can make juggling less annoying when you begin learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purpose-made: These are balls specifically made for juggling.
  I once juggled with them and I think they're much better than all other alternatives.
  But they're expensive and can usually only be bought online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beanbags and purpose-made balls are good, but they're either difficult to find or expensive.
That's why I have been using tennis balls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy an extra ball so that when you lose a ball,
you can keep practicing till you get a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Choose an environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you don't have breakables in your environment (unless you're juggling with sponge balls).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The place should be well lit (this makes much more difference than most people think).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The place should have a high enough ceiling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you can recover balls if they roll away
  (for example, under the furniture if you're juggling at home, or into bushes if you're juggling in a park).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a student in a hostel, a common room is often a good place to juggle.
Hostel corridors are generally also good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to not juggle in the exact same place facing in the exact same direction every time.
If you do that, you'll get used to a particular environment and it might be difficult to juggle elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other advice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep nails short to avoid injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get in the habit of counting your throws so that you can track your progress.
Sometimes you'll not see any progress for a few days despite regular practice.
Sometimes your performance could be less than the previous day.
Such incidences sometimes mean that your technique is incorrect.
But it usually happens to me for no obvious reason.
Don't give up. That's normal as far as I know. You'll eventually make progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Things to be vigilant about while juggling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a list of things you should be vigilant about while juggling.
If you can ensure all of these, you'll make progress faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep a correct stance. Feet should be at shoulder distance. This will increase stability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humerus"&gt;humerus&lt;/a&gt; should be roughly perpendicular to the ground.
  This will keep the juggling pattern plane at the right distance from you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radius_(bone)"&gt;radius&lt;/a&gt; and
  &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ulna"&gt;ulna&lt;/a&gt; should be roughly perpendicular to the humerus.
  This will keep the juggling pattern at the correct height.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For patterns with simple throws, there should be low variance in catch points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep the pattern in a plane parallel to yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're repeatedly throwing too forward, try holding on to props for longer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't rotate yourself while juggling (unless that's an intended trick).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid jerk throws, i.e giving a very large acceleration to balls for a very short time
  (heavy balls sometimes help prevent jerk throws).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid looking funny (for example, some people open their mouth while juggling high patterns).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Good luck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all! Keep practicing regularly and you'll soon be able to juggle the cascade.
I'll soon post another tutorial where I'll write about what you should learn next.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Juggling"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category></entry><entry><title>How I began Juggling</title><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/how-i-began-juggling.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-12-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Eklavya Sharma</name></author><id>tag:sharmaeklavya2.github.io,2017-12-02:/blog/how-i-began-juggling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since childhood, juggling had captivated me and I always wanted to learn how to juggle.
However, all my initial attempts to learn it failed. It was so difficult.
I couldn't make any progress even when I tried for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one day (in 2011, when I was around 16 years …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since childhood, juggling had captivated me and I always wanted to learn how to juggle.
However, all my initial attempts to learn it failed. It was so difficult.
I couldn't make any progress even when I tried for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one day (in 2011, when I was around 16 years old),
I saw a documentary-ish thing on TV about juggling.
According to it, there are multiple ways of juggling. Those ways are called 'patterns'.
The pattern below is called the 'shower' pattern:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Shower pattern" src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/51.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out that the shower is a difficult juggling pattern.
There's a juggling pattern easier than the shower, called 'cascade':&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cascade pattern" src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/3.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All my life, I had been trying to learn the shower
because that was the only juggling pattern I could imagine.
But as soon as I realized that cascade was easier, I tried learning that instead.
And this time I made some progress.
After around a week of practice, I could juggle for up to 10 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't remember why, but I didn't pursue juggling any further then.
I resumed it 3 years later.
I got better at cascade and then started learning other juggling patterns (including the shower).
Near the end of my first year at BITS (2014),
I bought juggling &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juggling_club"&gt;clubs&lt;/a&gt;.
By October 2017, I knew around 25 patterns with 3 balls, 8 patterns with 4 balls, the 5-ball cascade
and 7 patterns with 3 clubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't make much progress in 2016 and 2017.
I have been busy with studies and haven't been able to juggle regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find videos documenting my juggling skills on youtube:
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xYrnQMHfDNE&amp;amp;list=PLACN_dyOcd_WSIzGV-4hVCQyQFmzKH1kb"&gt;Juggling by me (October 2015)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Juggling"></category><category term="About Me"></category></entry><entry><title>How to juggle 3 balls in 1 hand</title><link href="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/3-in-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Eklavya Sharma</name></author><id>tag:sharmaeklavya2.github.io,2017-11-14:/blog/3-in-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/60.gif" title="60" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 balls in 1 hand, a.k.a. 3-in-1, is definitely not an easy pattern,
mostly because of the speed, accuracy and strength required to do it.
I could learn to do it because I came up with good prerequisites.
It still took me a few months to learn it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/60.gif" title="60" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 balls in 1 hand, a.k.a. 3-in-1, is definitely not an easy pattern,
mostly because of the speed, accuracy and strength required to do it.
I could learn to do it because I came up with good prerequisites.
It still took me a few months to learn it and I still haven't mastered it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this tutorial, I'll assume that you want to juggle 3 balls in your right hand.
If you want to juggle with your left hand, just mirror-invert all instructions here.
In all &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Siteswap"&gt;siteswaps&lt;/a&gt; mentioned here,
the first throw will be from the right hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, you should have mastered the 3 ball shower (siteswap &lt;code&gt;51&lt;/code&gt;) to almost perfection.
There are 2 mirror-images of the shower.
You must perfect the one where the left hand makes the horizontal pass
(i.e. siteswap &lt;code&gt;51&lt;/code&gt;, not &lt;code&gt;15&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you must learn to make a type-6 throw.
While juggling &lt;code&gt;51&lt;/code&gt;, replace one of the type-5 throws by a type-6 throw.
It'll look similar to &lt;code&gt;6151505151515151&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/6151505151515151.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;6151505151515151&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practice this until you find it easy to replace a type-5 throw by a type-6 throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now practice &lt;code&gt;615150&lt;/code&gt;, then &lt;code&gt;6051&lt;/code&gt;, then &lt;code&gt;61615050&lt;/code&gt; and then &lt;code&gt;606150&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="gallery"&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/615150.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;615150&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/6051.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;6051&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/61615050.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;61615050&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://sharmaeklavya2.github.io/blog/img/siteswaps/606150.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;606150&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might also want to try out other variations.
After you get good at these, you can finally try 3-in-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might also like this &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z2k3ugex7Kw"&gt;video tutorial by Chris Taibbi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Juggling"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category></entry></feed>